

# Jessica Miller

#### **EDUCATOR**

- 11445 Audrain Road 9907 Mexico, MO 65265
- millerjes0506@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/jessica-miller-400b111b2/

#### **PROFILE**

I have 10 years teaching experience. For the past four years I have been implementing technology within my classroom. I am proficient in Google Suites which includes implementing Google Classroom. I have excellent written and verbal communication skills with colleges and parents. I have trained and mentored other educators whom are both new and old in the district. My goal is to use my love for technology and teaching to help others become comfortable with utilizing it in their classroom or daily life.

#### SKILLS

**Detailed Oriented** 

•••••••

**Problem Solving** 

••••••

Creativity

.....

Leadership

**Effective Communication** 

••••••

**Excellent Work Ethic** 

••••••

**Technology Driven** 

•••••

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### MIDDLE SCHOOL SCIENCE & ROBOTICS INSTRUCTOR

# Missouri Military Academy

Aug 2019 - Present

- Co-Chair of the Technology Committee
- Utilizes 1-1 technology in the classroom
- Lead source on the application of technology and resources
- Professional Development for Educators: Nearpod
- Proficient in Google Classroom applications
- Developed and implemented lesson plans for Middle School Science, Math, and Robotics.
- Developed and implemented lesson plans for High School Geometry
- Teacher of the Semester Fall 2019

#### HIGH SCHOOL MATH INSTRUCTOR

# Casey-Westfield High School

Aug 2018 - May 2019

- Utilizes 1-1 technology in the classroom
- Experienced in Google Classroom Applications
- Developed and implemented lesson plans for High School Algebra 2, Algebra 1, and Concepts of Geometry
- Conducted remedial math intervention for 10th grade

#### MIDDLE SCHOOL MATH INSTRUCTOR

# Mayo Middle School

Aug 2017 - May 2018

- Collaborated in team meetings at the 8th-grade level
- Created rigorousPARCC aligned assessments
- Developed and implemented lesson plans for 8th-grade mathematics

#### **EDUCATION HISTORY**

# Masters in Elementary & Middle School Math

Jun 2015 - May 2018

# Eastern Illinois University

- Overall GPA: 3.82/4.0
- Middle School endorsement
- Action Research Project: The Use of Interactive Notebooks in

the Mathematics Classroom Setting

# BA in Mathematics

# Eastern Illinois University

Jan 2010- Dec 2012

- Overall GPA: 3.38/40 Major GPA: 3.27/4.0
- Mathematics with 6-12 teaching certificate
- Study Abroad in Toronto: Toronto for Teachers